<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to Poo Colour Decoder on Poo Colour Decoder</title>
    <link>https://poopcolor.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to Poo Colour Decoder on Poo Colour Decoder</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://poopcolor.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What happens to the colour of my poo when I take antibiotics</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/what-happens-to-the-colour-of-my-poo-when-i-take-antibiotics-2025-05-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/what-happens-to-the-colour-of-my-poo-when-i-take-antibiotics-2025-05-04/</guid>
      <description>Discover how antibiotics affect your poop color, reasons for changes, and when to consult a doctor for safe digestive health awareness.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bile Salts and Golden Stool</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/bilesalt-2025-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/bilesalt-2025-04-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Balanced bile production yields a golden-brown hue. If you skip a meal or take antacids, you might see slight variations—but golden is typically normal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;. Not medical advice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is My Poo Pale - common causes</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-poo-pale-common-causes-2025-04-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-poo-pale-common-causes-2025-04-29/</guid>
      <description>Discover common causes of pale poo, symptoms to watch for, and when to see a doctor for potential liver or digestive issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is My Poo Yellow? 7 Common Causes</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-poo-yellow-7-common-causes-2025-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-poo-yellow-7-common-causes-2025-04-28/</guid>
      <description>Discover 7 common causes of yellow poo, including diet, digestion issues, and infections, to understand your bowel health better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Stool After Iron Supplements: What to Know</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/black-stool-after-iron-supplements-what-to-know-2025-04-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/black-stool-after-iron-supplements-what-to-know-2025-04-27/</guid>
      <description>Discover why black stool occurs after iron supplements, its causes, when to worry, and tips for managing side effects effectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blood in Stool vs Red Foods: How to Tell</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/blood-in-stool-vs-red-foods-how-to-tell-2025-04-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/blood-in-stool-vs-red-foods-how-to-tell-2025-04-27/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to distinguish blood in stool from red-colored foods with expert tips to identify causes and when to seek help.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is My Stool Green? 7 Common Causes</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-stool-green-7-common-causes-2025-04-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-stool-green-7-common-causes-2025-04-27/</guid>
      <description>Discover 7 common causes of green stool, symptoms to watch for, and when to see a doctor for digestive health concerns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bile Acid Diarrhea</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/bile-acid-diarrhea-2025-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/bile-acid-diarrhea-2025-04-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that bile acid diarrhea can give your stool a colorful makeover? Normally, bile acids help digest fats and give stool its typical brown color. But when bile acids aren’t absorbed properly and rush into the colon, they can cause diarrhea—and that speedy travel can also change stool color! You might notice brighter, greener, or even yellowish hues popping up. It’s like your digestive system’s way of showing off a bit of flair! This color change happens because bile acids interact differently with the gut bacteria and digestive juices when they’re out of place. So next time you see a surprising shade in the bathroom, remember: your body’s chemistry is at work, painting a unique digestive story! How’s that for a colorful twist in gut health?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dehydration And Hard Stool</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/dehydration-and-hard-stool-2025-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/dehydration-and-hard-stool-2025-04-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that dehydration can not only make your stool hard but also change its color? When you don’t drink enough water, your body pulls extra fluids from your waste before it&amp;rsquo;s ready to leave your body. This makes your poop harder and often darker—think deep brown or even blackish! On the flip side, if you’re super hydrated, your stool tends to be softer and lighter brown, signaling a well-watered digestive journey. Color changes in your stool are like little mood rings for your tummy, giving you clues about what’s happening inside. So next time you notice a color shift, it might just be your body’s colorful way of saying, “Hey, maybe sip some water!” Fun, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Fat Meals And Yellow Stool</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/high-fat-meals-and-yellow-stool-2025-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/high-fat-meals-and-yellow-stool-2025-04-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that your stool can turn a surprising shade of yellow after indulging in high-fat meals? It&amp;rsquo;s a little color adventure that happens because of bile, which is a digestive fluid produced by your liver. When you munch on fatty foods like that delicious cheesy pizza or a yummy ice cream sundae, your body goes into overdrive, producing more bile to break down all that fat. If the fat doesn’t get fully absorbed, it can whisk the bile through your intestines quicker than usual, adding a sunny yellow hue to your stool. So next time you notice a little burst of sunshine in the toilet bowl, you might just have those tempting, fat-packed treats to thank!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Stools Turn Mysterious Hues</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/when-stools-turn-mysterious-hues-2025-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/when-stools-turn-mysterious-hues-2025-04-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When stools suddenly change color, it’s like your digestive system’s way of throwing a little colorful surprise! Different hues can pop up due to various harmless reasons. For instance, eating lots of beets can tint your stool a reddish-purple, while spinach or other leafy greens might turn it green. Sometimes, medicine or supplements, like iron pills, can darken stools to almost black. Yellow stools can indicate that food is moving through the gut a bit too quickly, mixing with extra bile that gives it that buttery shade. And pale or clay-colored stools? They happen when bile pigments, which usually give stool its brown tone, are temporarily low. So next time you spot an unexpected color in the bowl, remember—it’s often just your body’s colorful way of saying, “Hey, check out what I’m digesting today!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is My Stool Changing Color? Foods, Meds, Infections Causes</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-stool-changing-color-foods-meds-infections-causes-2025-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-stool-changing-color-foods-meds-infections-causes-2025-04-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that your stool’s color can be like a little daily report from your digestive system? Normally, it’s brown thanks to a pigment called bilirubin, which comes from the breakdown of old red blood cells. But sometimes, what you eat or take can change this color! For example, eating lots of beets can turn your stool reddish, while foods with spinach or iron supplements might give it a greenish tint. Even medications like some antibiotics or antacids can cause surprising color shifts. Infections can also make stool look different, often causing yellow or pale stools. So, your stool’s color is actually a vibrant mix of your diet, medications, and how your body’s working—a colorful little clue to how things are going inside!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is My Stool Dark After Taking Iron Pills or Antibiotics?</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-stool-dark-after-taking-iron-pills-or-antibiotics-2025-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/why-is-my-stool-dark-after-taking-iron-pills-or-antibiotics-2025-04-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that taking iron pills or certain antibiotics can turn your stool dark, sometimes almost black? This color change is actually quite common and happens because iron supplements introduce extra iron into your digestive system. When iron mixes with digestive fluids, it creates a darker pigment, giving your stool a deep, sometimes tar-like appearance. Similarly, some antibiotics can alter your gut bacteria or interact with meals, which might also affect stool color. It’s a harmless side effect showing how what you swallow can directly influence what comes out! So next time your stool looks like a midnight snack after popping those pills, it’s just your body’s colorful response to your treatment journey. Pretty cool, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beetroot and Red Stool</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/red-poo-beetroot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/red-poo-beetroot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beetroot contains betalains—vibrant pigments that pass through the gut.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Eating beetroot can cause pink or red stools, a harmless and temporary effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Supplements and Black Stool</title>
      <link>https://poopcolor.info/posts/black-poo-iron/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://poopcolor.info/posts/black-poo-iron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Iron tablets can darken the stool colour significantly, turning it black or dark green.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This change is common and reflects unabsorbed iron passing through the intestines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*&lt;em&gt;. Not medical advice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
